criticalpast.com 2014-06-30

# CriticalPast.com: Privacy Policy

###### Privacy Policy

We have created this Privacy Policy because we are committed to your privacy. The following discloses our information gathering and dissemination practices. This policy covers all Critical Past LLC properties including, but not limited to the following domains: CriticalPast.com, CriticalPast.co.uk, and all other sites owned or operated by Critical Past LLC.  

######   
PERSONAL INFORMATION

Any personal information that you provide to our Web site will stay safe, private, and secure. We will not resell your information to outside sources. We will not share your information with any third parties with the exception of verified secure ecommerce transaction providers.

######   
INFORMATION THAT WE MAY COLLECT FROM OUR USERS

We may collect the following information when you sign up for a service:   
• First name, last name, company name, e-mail, address, phone number  
• For processing transactions, we also collect either credit card information or bank information, depending on your form of payment.

######   
IP Address:

When a user visits any Web site owned or operated by Critical Past LLC, we may collect the IP address that requested the display of one of our sites. This address is collected for several purposes. The first purpose is to exercise our ability to restrict access to the site by users who have violated our Terms of Service. A second purpose is to support our advertising partners, so that the partners will be able to accurately count the number of unique visitors to our sites who may have viewed a given advertisement. Finally, if you participate in our "Send to a Friend" feature, your IP address will be shared with the person to whom you send a clip to using this feature.

######   
Registration and Sign In information:

Any information you provide to us as part of your use of any Critical Past LLC Web site will be stored as entered.

######   
Cookies:

The sole purpose of cookies is to enhance your online experience. Cookies are small data files that are stored on your computer by Web sites. Through your Web browser, cookies are only used by the Web site that wrote the cookie. Data stored in a cookie from Critical Past LLC is only accessible by the Critical Past LLC Web sites. Personal information stored in our cookies is limited to: Shopping Cart affiliate identifier, Principal Network Partner affiliate identifier, and your Username. This information enables us to run our affiliate programs, allows customized advertising, lets you automatically sign in when you visit Critical Past LLC, and offers other operational site activities. The information in our cookies is kept private and secure.

######   
USE OF COLLECTED INFORMATION

Your username, e-mail address, and password will be used to uniquely identify you as a user on any Critical Past LLC Web site. We may use or display your username within our "More info or Correction" pages or "Forum" discussion pages. Other identifying information collected during the sign up process or through other voluntary means may be used to calculate aggregate demographic figures or to facilitate our ability to direct advertisements to your Web browser. In addition, if you participate in our "Send to a Friend" feature, your IP address will be shared with the person to whom you send a clip to using this feature.

######   
SECURITY OF COLLECTED INFORMATION

All data that we collect is stored on one or more secure database servers that cannot be accessed from outside our corporate network. Outside of our network, the only access to this data is that provided through our Web sites. Through our sites, access to personal information is completely controlled by user-defined e-mail addresses and passwords. Within our corporation, access to data is secured through a private user ID and password known only to key personnel who maintain the database. All employees of Critical Past LLC are legally bound by a nondisclosure agreement that prevents the disclosure of any corporate information to other parties. We have taken all reasonable precautions to safeguard the privacy of your data.

######   
OTHER INFORMATION COLLECTED

Your Web browser or client software that you use to access Critical Past LLC may transmit certain geographic information and information regarding the capabilities or features of your computer and/or software to us. We may also track other types of information, such as what clips users play, how long our users have been members of any Critical Past LLC businesses or programs, the last time a user visited Critical Past LLC, and whether a user has licensed any of our clips, images, or other media. We may use this information to calculate aggregate statistics about our user community or for security purposes, and may provide such information to advertisers and/or partners in aggregate form only.

######   
HOW INFORMATION IS USED

The information you provide to Critical Past LLC will allow us to notify you about resolution of site problems, handle and/or route your customer support questions and issues, and inform you of the status of orders and other licensing activities. Critical Past LLC may use personal information in combination with data from third parties for similar purposes as well.

######   
THIRD-PARTY ADVERTISING

It is important that you understand that advertisers or Web sites that link to a Critical Past LLC site may collect personal information about you. The Privacy Policy does not apply to, and cannot control the activities of, other advertisers or Web sites. We use third-party advertising companies to serve ads on our sites. These companies may use information about your visits to this and other sites in order to help them provide relevant ads to users (this information does not include name, address, e-mail address, or telephone number).

######   
SHARING INFORMATION

Critical Past LLC may disclose your personal information if there is a violation of the Terms of Service or if we have a good faith belief that the law requires it. It is also important that you understand that we cannot control the activities of third-party vendors, such as advertisers. While we cannot guarantee that they will adhere to the same privacy and security procedures as Critical Past LLC, we will take all reasonable precautions under the circumstances to ensure the protection of your personal information.

######   
FORUMS AND MESSAGING

Critical Past LLC sites may choose to operate message boards and/or forum areas where users can exchange ideas and communicate with one another. When posting to a message board or forum area, it is important for you to understand that the information is being made publicly available in an online environment. Any information posted is the sole responsibility of the individual user.

######   
Are you concerned about our use of personal information?

If, for any reason, you are concerned with the way that we may be using your personal information, you may request that we cease to use your information or you may file a complaint by contacting Critical Past LLC, 12100 Sunrise Valley Drive, Box E-230-16 Reston, Virginia 20191 U.S.A.

######   
AGREEMENT WITH CRITICALPAST LLC POLICIES

By using any of the Critical Past LLC Web sites, products, or services, you signify your understanding and agreement to the Privacy Policy stated here, and to the Terms of Use. If you do not agree with our policies, please do not use any of the Critical Past LLC Web sites, products, or services.
